Guide to the The Seminar on American Architecture: Design of the American College Campus, Student Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Seminar on American Architecture: Design of the American College Campus, student papers
1986-2005
SC0355
Stanford University
0.75 Linear feet
Collection consists of student papers produced through course work and covering the academic years 1986-1988 and 1999, with series arrangement reflecting the course year.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of student authors, 1986-1988 and 2004.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Seminar on American Architecture: The Design of the American College Campus, a writing-intensive course, sponsored by Art Professor Paul Turner, was crated in 1986 to survey and address architecture and campus planning as developed at college and universities in the United States using the campus of Stanford University as a model for development.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of student papers produced through course work and covering the academic years 1986-1988 and 1999, with series arrangement reflecting the course year.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Art Department.; Turner, Paul Venable; Architecture, Modern --20th century.; Campus Planning.
Collection Contents
- 1999 Papers
  - Michelson, Alan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ortel, Jo, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Geyling, R., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harband, D., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Leonse, E., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lee, S.Y., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Leung, J.S., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pearson, Andrew, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wayne, K., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gallagher, Rache l. Stanford's Medical Center: Constructing a Teaching College on a University Campus, Dec. 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Griffin, Corey. The Return to Olmsted's Vision: A Study of Undergraduate Dormitories at Stanford, Dec. 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Uffelman, Daisy. The Science and Engineering Quad: A Contemporary Interpretation of Olmsted's Original Plans for the Stanford Campus, ec. 2, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vora, Ashish. Bridging the Gap: The History and Role of Student Unions at Stanford, Dec. 2, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Yih, Pau l. Humanizing Academia in the Machine Age: Lewis Mumford's Influence on Circulation and Parking Planning at Stanford, Dec. 15, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 2005 Papers
  - Heckenlively, Bryan H. Stanford Law School: Crown and Gown, May 31, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pfeiffer, Katie. The Realization of a Dream: the Women's Clubhouse at Stanford, May 30, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Richardson, Tom. SEQ 2: Olmsted's Vision and the Future of Stanford University, May 31, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Willis, Ellen. Stanford's Cottage System, May 31, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)